<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description>ok</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>San Francisco, California</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;exits car&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;nearly passes out from the smell of weed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;steps onto broken glass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;oh what a nic—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;trips over homeless man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;n-ni—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;gets erratically yelled at&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nice neighborhood….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;turns around to see car with no tires and a ticket for parking on grades&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;flies back to france&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/blog/2019/08/04/sf.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019/08/04/sf.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>AN ENTREPRENEUR'S GUIDE TO SUCCESSFULLY SCOUTING THE WEST COAST</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;it’s sunday and i’ve made an entrepreneurial gamble that involves wandering off into yogi bear territory. the drive up is “pretty neat” around mt shasta but gets more tedious thereafter. i won’t complain. scouting is part of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my intel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;portland is like if you take out pittsburgh’s college town vibe and diversity and stick in white guys with tattoos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and suburban moms and hippies wearing no shirts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in eugene i went to this coffee/donut shop that had a guy in the back who made thai food. i wonder who propositioned who. in the middle of my donut this incredibly white family pulled up in a soccer mom van and out came four teenaged kids. polo shirt, cargo shorts, long nike socks, athletic shoes. one girl. i bet the boys carved a hole in the bathroom wall to sneak peaks before church. mom and dad stayed in the car. dad looked disgruntled. maybe his sermon didn’t go too well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;seattle on the other hand is DYING according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/bpAi70WWBlw&quot;&gt;this nice video&lt;/a&gt; about homeless fellas on youtube. the people here don’t seem too spooked though. if anything seattle is dying from the inside. fremont feels like some boomer heard about hipsters and made a cafe and bar oriented theme park around “quirkiness” ex-dee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in other news amazon is moving out to bellevue with microsoft in the next few years removing another major draw to the inner city. assumedly after they arrive they’ll hike up the housing cost and censor “head tax” from all company buildings in a CCP like fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’m sitting in the university district right now. it’s nice in a generic way. i’d still prefer berkeley for this kinda thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i guess it’s not the 90s anymore. if the west coast was ever hip and artsy and diverse and cool all the artists have moved to random neighborhoods in LA where they can actually afford to be poor and unsuccessful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or they’ve found their niche on the internet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;god bless? god bless&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/blog/2019/08/04/guide3.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019/08/04/guide3.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>GUIDE TO SUCCESSFULLY BECOMING AN ENTREPRENEUR</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;one day you’ll wake up in silicon valley and realize all you need in life is toothpaste, a toothbrush, and a laptop. and a girlfriend with a shower and a club key that gives you access to a spa. so you ditch the idea of workawaying and decide to sleep in your car. OK. this is just step one. some would call this homeless but it’s really just the entrepreneurial spirit. an entrepreneur needs to be focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wake up each morning and pray in the direction of apple park. then sit at the local starbucks in cupertino and work on programming your new startup idea. tape a picture of your future tesla to the back of your macbook and stare at it whenever you feel discouraged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the car you just bought is still there whenever you need to sob in it. you’re getting plenty of value out of it by doing this. if you put the backseat of your car on airbnb in the bay area you could sell it for forty dollars a night with a twenty dollar cleaning fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;look for networking events in your area on facebook. inform everyone at the talk that they’re statistically only going to hire one or two people in this crowd of 100 but you have an unbelievable opportunity for the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/blog/2019/07/26/guide2.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019/07/26/guide2.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>GUIDE TO SUCCCESSFULLY PURCHASING A VEHICLE IN A DIFFERENT STATE WHILE NOT COMPLETELY ABANDONING YOUR OLD ONE</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;so hopefully by now you blew your engine on the highway and instead of giving up and going home your first thought was “oh… well I guess I gotta buy a new car!” so you rode 5 hours in the wrong direction and began your search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;before this you should’ve established that you towed your car to a service shop that didn’t charge daily storage fees or $100 to tell you that something is horribly, irrepairably wrong. and i bet you’re regretting skipping that oil change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this step was brought on by the friendly highway patrol man giving you the friendliest threat in the world. essentially:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“hi! you have two hours to remove the vehicle from the highway or it’ll be impounded with all your stuff! here’s some water btw don’t die lol i’ll be back later”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;since there’s no rush according to the service shop (right? call and confirm that), you can get AAA premium and tow it for free up to 200 miles after a 3 day initial membership. if that’s not enough time, just get it on the way back. if that’s not enough miles, hope you have a friend who can hitch it with a truck or you’re willing to pay more to tow it farther&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;just remember, you’re in god’s favorite country, and there’s always a liquor store nearby, and that’s all the moral support you need. keep that in mind as you wait 6 hours for your friend from iowa to pick you up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyways, back to car purchasing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you need to establish the following information to see how possible this is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you register the vehicle in the state you’re purchasing it from without being a resident? (in my case, no)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does your state of residency allow registration by mail? (in my case, no)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you insure the vehicle with your state of residency’s insurance even though it’s registered in another state? (surprisingly, in my case, yes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can find all this out through calling insurance agents and the DMVs of both states. even a dealership just to get started (even though you totally aren’t buying a car from them)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;let’s assume the second worst possible case which may or may not have been mine - you can’t register the car in the state you’re buying it from and you can’t register it in your home state until you get back. and you’re traveling for more than 30 days so a temp plate won’t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;remember the friend that picked you up? do you guys trust each other?…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;since he’s a resident, transfer the title at the DMV to a co-ownership under the “OR” option (meaning either can act as the sole owner and sell it without the other’s signature), then have it co-registered with his name listed first. this’ll get you license plates. just note the co-registration under the insurance and insure it yourself. unless the answer to #3 is also no.. in which case you have to pay off your friend to insure it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as for finding a car wherever you are, good luck, just make sure you take it to a well-rated mechanic to have it checked out before you buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;once again it’s all about who you know. so much for your emergency funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;make sure to take solace in the fact that your final destination is only the second most expensive metro in the US. sob quietly in your new car when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/media/bye.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;car one&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/media/hello.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;car two&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>/blog/2019/07/08/guide.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019/07/08/guide.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>vagueness and knowability</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;as i write this, i’ve now graduated, but i still think the main idea behind my senior thesis is both plausible and interesting. i mostly 
stumbled upon it. it uses topological epistemic semantics to model Williamson’s epistemicism using the concept of knowability while preserving the KK principle (which has been traditionally discarded by proponents of epistemicism). for more of an introduction: it has to do with the problem of vagueness, which is usually motivated via the Sorites paradox. here’s what i wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This paradox has two observations. One: there exist clear cut cases for most predicates. Let $B(x)$ be defined as ‘the entity x is bald.’ Clearly, if $x$ has 0 hairs on his head, then $B(x)$ is true. Two: if there is a clear cut case, some other imperceptibly different case should have the same truth value. Let $x$ be some clear cut case of baldness - say $x$ has 4 hairs on his head. And let $y$ have 1 more hair on his head than $x$. it seems to be the case that $y$ is also, without need for inspection, bald. This is usually formalized in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{align*}
&amp;(1) &amp; P(0) \\
&amp;(2) &amp; \forall n (P(n) \rightarrow P(n+1)) \\
\hline 
&amp; &amp; \forall n P(n)
\end{align*} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;in the derivative above, the first and second premises correspond to the first and second observations. But, if you substitute ‘B’ in for ‘P’ in the formula above, this implies that a man with a full head of hair (say, $n := 1,000,000$) is bald. A sorites series is just some series of Modus Ponens that follows this formula to such an effect, like claiming that a man with a full head of hair is bald. Now, we can state what it means to be vague: a predicate, $P$, is vague just in case it can be used to generate a Sorites series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the last line isn’t exactly true – the Sorites paradox is only one lense through which to view vagueness. the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/vagueness/&quot;&gt;Stanford philosophy article&lt;/a&gt; is worth reading for more of a background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the Sorites paradox might bug you because it seems to imply that either premise (2) is incorrect, i.e. there is some clearly bald person such that adding one hair to their head makes them clearly not bald, or there is something wrong with classical logic, i.e. we should adopt another logic with a different semantics that muddies the cases between ‘clearly bald’ and ‘clearly not bald.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my thesis models vagueness as an epistemic phenomena regarding &lt;em&gt;knowability&lt;/em&gt;. in parallel, i argue that my proposed model for vagueness also clearly fits a brand of epistemicism (the idea that preserves classical logic but claims that premise (2) is actually false; if a man is clearly bald with $n$ hairs on his head, it may be the case that he is clearly not bald with $n+1$ hairs on his head. the only problem is that such boundaries are, by nature, unknowable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’ll let the thesis introduce what i take to be the central tenant of epistemicism, margin for error principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As defined by Williamson, “A &lt;em&gt;margin for error principle&lt;/em&gt; is a principle of the form: ‘A’ is true in all cases similar to cases in which ‘it is known that A’ is true. Which margin for error principles obtain depends on the circumstances.” The idea behind this is intuitive. We might think of similar cases as cases in which the differences are imperceptible, or nearly so. For instance, if you walk into a room with 5 people in it, and you are trying to estimate how many people are in the room, the required degree of similarity might be determined by some trace amount of atoms. But if you walk into a stadium filled with people and you are faced with the same task, the degree of similarity could include dozens of people, as your senses are only so perfect - there could be people around the corner or behind a wall that you do not see; in this case, knowledge may be categorized as “inexact.” So, since we want knowledge to be &lt;em&gt;reliable&lt;/em&gt;, to say ‘it is known that A’ is just to say that, in all reasonably similar cases, ‘A’ is true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hold any thoughts! i’m condensing things haphazardly. at this point it’d be good to gain a basic familiarity with the epistemic interpretation of the topological semantics for modal logic. a gentle introduction can be read &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1803.08193.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. or, just keep reading and take the math at face value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;using the topological semantics, i define what it means for a predicate $P$ to be vague at a world $w$ as such:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;V_w(P) \text{ iff } \exists x (\neg \square Px \wedge \neg \square \neg Px)&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This reads that a predicate $P$ is vague if and only if there is some entity $x$ in its domain such that it’s not knowable whether $x$ is $P$ and it’s not knowable whether $x$ is not $P$. Thus $x$ is referred to as a “borderline case,” and the existence of borderline cases implies a predicate is vague. it’s worth reflecting on the geometric interpretation here. Assume that &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;int( [\![Px]\!] )&lt;/script&gt; is non-empty. Also, observe that, in classical logic, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[\![Px]\!] = [\![\neg Px]\!]^\complement&lt;/script&gt;. This gives the following picture for a vague predicate’s borderline case&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/media/vg.png&quot; alt=&quot;vagueness&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;$w$ actually rests on the border between &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[\![Px]\!] \text{ and } [\![\neg Px]\!]&lt;/script&gt;. Any open set $U$, where $w \in U$, will contain other worlds that satisfy both $Px$ and $\neg Px$. A philosophical picture is also painted: learning that a predicate or category is vague is an inductive process - one that follows investigation and common sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now, to tie the topological semantics back to margin for error principles, i let the thesis continue from before:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Without directly invoking topological semantics, we could formalize this notion at a world $w$ as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\begin{align*}
\text{if } w  \models K(A),\text{ then } \exists U \text{ such that } U \subseteq [\![A]\!], U \text{ is an open set}
\end{align*}&lt;/script&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here, the open set $U$ just represents some “cluster” of similarity. &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[\![A]\!]&lt;/script&gt; is the positive extension of A - all worlds w such that ‘A’ is true at w. However, note that if there is some open set &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; such that $w \in U$, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;U \subseteq [\![A]\!]&lt;/script&gt; then it follows that &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w \in int( [\![A]\!] )&lt;/script&gt;. Thus we have:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\text{if } w \models K(A), \text{ then } w \models \square A \qquad \qquad (Ki)&lt;/script&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This simply reads “if ‘A’ is known, then ‘A’ is knowable.” This should intuitively be the case. Thus, i argue that topological semantics give a straightforward, natural model of the margin for error principle, as the box operator is just a realization of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we can use this isomorphism to address the Sorites paradox in a way Williamson does not. if you begin to wonder where the knowledge predicate, K, comes from, remember that we are modeling vagueness epistemically, thus the Sorites paradox should correspondingly be on an epistemic level. continuing on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to Williamson, margin for error principles describe how our knowledge can be vague. Consider the special case where we have a proposition of the form ‘it is known that A’. Now apply a margin for error principle to it. We get: ‘it is known that A’ is true in all cases similar to cases in which ‘it is known that it is known that A’ is true. But, as Williamson claims, this can be a more stringent condition than the former. Our knowledge of our knowledge is inexact. The margin for error might need to be widened as it’s impacted by factors such as our “ability to judge reliably.” Thus, the $KK$ principle, where $Kp \rightarrow KKp$ for all propositions $p$, is false.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Vagueness also gives rise to margin for error principles. Consider a typical vague term like ‘heap.’ We should have the following, which Williamson labels (!)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\begin{align*}
\text{(!) if we know that n grains make a heap, then n-1 grains make a heap.}
\end{align*}&lt;/script&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The idea being, again, that we want knowledge to be reliable, so indiscernible differences should be evaluated the same way. With the $KK$ principle, and a $K$ operator which needs nothing more than the distribution axiom, we would generate a sorites series for ‘known heaps’ in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
\begin{align*}
(K(H(n)) \rightarrow H(n-1) &amp;\implies (KK(H(n)) \rightarrow K(H(n-1))  &amp;  (distribution) \\
										 &amp;\implies K(H(n-1)) 								   &amp; (KK) \\ 
										 &amp;\implies K(H(n)) \rightarrow K(H(n-1))
\end{align*} %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, with repeated modus ponens one will eventually reach the conclusion that a single grain is a known heap. However, as discussed above, the KK principle does not hold according to Williamson. Each successive iteration requires a widening of the margin of the first known heap as another $’K’$ is added. Thus, after some number of iterations, the antecedent will fail to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;remember, however, that we modeled the margin for error principle differently. and our model does not require denying the KK principle. thus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Assume, for the sake of argument, that (!) is true. Thus, as before, we have $\forall n, w \models K(H(n))$, and from (Ki), we get $\forall n, w \models \square H(n)$.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But if the predicate in question is vague, we have&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;V_w(P) \text{ iff } \exists n (\neg \square H(n) \wedge \neg \square \neg H(n))&lt;/script&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Thus, for some $n$, $ \neg \square H(n)$ and $\square H(n)$, which is a contradiction. So we must abandon the assumption, (!). Philosophically, this motivates a perspective where the discretization of ‘grains’ is too gross a scale for the similarity measure. Somewhere between $n$ and $n-1$ grains, for some $n$, there is a switch between being a heap and not. This may not be unreasonable - consider larger scale vague terms such as ‘several.’ Clearly it is not the case that, if we know ‘2 people is not several’ and ‘4 people is several’, it follows that ‘3 people is several’ is both true and false. Topological semantics dictate that the required similarity metric does not have to be quantized to the integers. And the center of each ‘measurement’ or ‘cluster’ need not be the entity at hand (in this case, $n$-people). Similarly it may be the case for terms such as ‘heap.’ it could just be that $n$-grains is on the edge of some $U$ in the positive extension of the ‘heap’ predicate as applied to $n$, and stepping to $n-1$ grains brings the entity outside of interior of the positive extension at our world $w$ – namely, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w \notin int( [\![H(n-1)]\!] )&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thus we have the basics of the model for vagueness. the rest of the thesis attempts to analyze higher order vagueness by sketchily equating the ‘definitely’ operator from supervaluationism with the ‘box’ operator from the topological semantics. it’s not fully convincing but it seems like the plausible analog and the results are interesting: we’d expect that, for any proposition p, either ‘definitely definitely p’ is true or ‘definitely not definitely p’ is true. but this is not true for the ‘box’ operator - it leaves out the worlds in the border in the picture above – meaning we have second order vagueness (it’s vague whether some predicates are vague). thus, our semantics are vague. so, for some predicates, any purported borderline case is no longer borderline in a slightly different context (world contained in the measurement &lt;em&gt;U&lt;/em&gt; containing &lt;em&gt;w&lt;/em&gt;). i.e., borderline cases are highly controversial; this might actually make sense given predicates like ‘x is &lt;em&gt;art&lt;/em&gt;’ or ‘x is &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt;.’ however, since the interior of the interior is the interior, &lt;em&gt;higher&lt;/em&gt; orders of vagueness are semantically identical to this second-order vagueness, making it much more precise than the higher order vagueness of supervaluationism or fuzzy logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is all worth investigating more. i did not begin to open the box of worms involved in cogently mixing modal operators with quantification (does this mean you quantify only over the entities at each domain? do you assume all predicates have the same domains at all worlds?).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>/thoughts/2019/01/02/knowability.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/thoughts/2019/01/02/knowability.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>foray</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;“ok”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>/2018/11/20/foray.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/2018/11/20/foray.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
